<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Speaking on Cave Confessions</title>
    <link>http://caveconfessions.com/tags/public-speaking/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Speaking on Cave Confessions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://caveconfessions.com/tags/public-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Make The Web SQueaL</title>
      <link>http://caveconfessions.com/make-the-web-squeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 07:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://caveconfessions.com/make-the-web-squeal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://caveconfessions.com/content/images/2014/Nov/SQueaL_Talk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;First Talk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave my first public talk last week. It was a talk on SQL Injection that was
given at this month&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/nolasecurity/&#34;&gt;NolaSec&lt;/a&gt;
meetup. And, I have to say, I really enjoyed the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-talk&#34;&gt;The Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk was titled &amp;ldquo;Make The Web SQueaL: An Introduction to
SQL Injection.&amp;rdquo; It was a pretty quick talk. The goal when written was to make a
20 minute-ish talk with room for questions at the end. And I think I got pretty
close to that. It was really geared to being purely introductory. To that end
it was very high level with a few slides devoted to what is SQL and SQL
Injection. Then moving on to how SQL Injection works, and what can be done with
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To go along with the talk I created a cool little lab environment, to help
demonstrate exactly what SQL Injection is, but I think I did a poor job of
introducing it at the end of the talk. My intent was to offer to demonstrate
after all the talks were concluded, but those words escaped me while I was up
there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbarone/SQueaL/releases/download/v0.1/Make_The_Web_SQueaL.pdf&#34;&gt;The
Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbarone/SQueaL&#34;&gt;The Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-experience&#34;&gt;The Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience, for me, was the best part of the
night. Many of my co-workers expressed interest in attending the meetup. I&amp;rsquo;ve
given a few talks within the company before, on similar topics. And apparently
that was enough to make them what to learn more and support me. It was
extremely gratifying, and nerve wracking at the same time. A good handful of my
coworkers made it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk itself made me a little nervous. During the introduction they pointed
out that it was probably one of the largest groups they have had attend one
these meetups. So, nothing like go big or go home. I presented my slides at a
pretty good clip, but I kept watching the faces in the crowd and from what I
could tell everyone was following. During the question and answer section. I
got a really good group of questions, that helped let me know that what I
talked about, was not only absorbed, but was being applied in their minds to
the work they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all. It was a great experience. And I very much look forward to doing it
again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>